# **George TZORTZOPOULOS**

I aim to take part in the creation of innovative and fun games, using modern technologies and gadgets while offering 5+ years of professional experience, skills and passion for quality games to a demanding and fast-paced environment with an eye on detail and aesthetics.

# **Key Skills and Knowledge**

#### **Skills**

#### Languages

- Proficient in: C++, C#, Java, Javascript, HTML, CSS, jQuery
- Familiar with: Python, SQL, PHP, R, LSL

#### Plugins, frameworks & SDKs

 Experienced in: NVidia GameWorks, ARCore, ARKit, Vuforia, Amplify Shader Editor, OpenCV, WPF, Django, Node.js, Handlebars, Marionette, Less.js

#### **Software**

- <u>Graphics Engines</u>: Unreal Engine 4, Unity3D, Proprietary Engines, OpenSim. Familiar with: CryEngine
- Platforms: PC, PS4, XB1, Android, iOS
- <u>IDEs</u>: Rider, Visual Studio, MonoDevelop, Code::Blocks, Eclipse, Android Studio, Xcode
- <u>3D Graphics Editors</u>: Maya 2017, Adobe Photoshop CC, MightyBake, Quixel, Marmoset Toolbag 3
- <u>Version Control</u>: Perforce, Git, SVN GUI's: P4V, GitKraken, Tortoise SVN, SourceTree, GitHub
- Also experienced in: pgAdmin, PostgreSQL, Matlab, RStudio, Adobe Dreamweaver, CMS (Joomla, Drupal), XAMPP, Windows Server 2016, Filezilla, MS Office

# **Experience**

### **DR Studios**

Gameplay Programmer

May 2021 - Present

- Duties: features development, debugging
- Skills acquired: gameplay programming, C++, UE4, replication, live-game workflow, team management

#### **Climax Studios**

Programmer

Jun 2020 - May 2021

- Duties: features development, debugging
- Skills acquired: gameplay programming, C++, proprietary engines, working on consoles (PS4, XB1), AAA games

#### Kylotonn

Gameplay Programmer

Oct 2018 - Mar 2019

- Duties: development of gameplay features
- Skills acquired: gameplay programming, C++, proprietary engines, input, UI, shaders, collaboration with designers and artists, game production procedure

# **Personal Info**

O Nationality: Greek

**Age:** 32

**Address**:

Orfeos 12 Palaio Faliro 17564, Greece

Phone:

+30 6942991517

@ Email:

george.tzortzopoulos@gmail.com

**Website:** 

www.gtzortzopoulos.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ge
orge-tzortzopoulos/

O GitHub:

https://github.com/Gheldar

Skype:

george.tzortzopoulos@gmail.com

#### **Okénite Animation**

Developer

Feb 2018 - Sep 2018

- Duties: development of real-time rendered applications, asset integration, R&D, modelling-texturing & model optimization
- Skills acquired: game development, game editor plugins and modification, VR/AR, modelling principles for realtime applications, optimization according to hardware, object/image recognition, high-level design

## Fremen Corp

Developer (Intern)

Iun 2017 - Dec 2017

- Duties: full-stack development and modifications of serious games and gamification of applications
- Skills acquired: game development, web application development, mobile development, working under clients' specifications, QA

# **Projects**

**Professional** – Participating in the development of various professional projects concerning

- Games
- VR/AR
- Serious games and gamified applications
- E-learning web applications

#### **Notable mentions:**

- Hawken Reborn Gameplay programmer and owner of gameplay related systems for an online, liveservice game, while managing the Gameplay code
- **EA Sports PGA Tour** Generalist programming in various domains including gameplay, rendering etc.
- **Destruction AllStars** Accessibility work for the upcoming PS5 game, using C++ on UE4
- **WRC 8** Gameplay programming for the official game of the WRC championship, using C++ on a proprietary engine.

(refer to the portfolio for more projects and information)

#### **Education**

**University of Piraeus** (Greece) – Bachelor in Informatics *Software Engineering and Intelligent Systems* 

**University of Castilla-La Mancha** (Spain) Erasmus in Informatics

#### Languages:

Greek (native), English (proficient), French (intermediate), Spanish (intermediate)

**Seminars:** Various (e.g. Social networks, security & privacy etc. Details upon request)

## **Interests**

**Gaming** – Having experienced many generations of games, I spend a lot of my personal time playing both casual and competitive games of various game genres, while I also tend to be up-to-date in relation to gaming news and share them with the people around me

**Music** – I play various musical instruments, with drums being the one that passionates me the most, I have had various releases and live performances

**Cartoons** – I love cartoons, including both American as well as Japanese anime

**Gadgets** – I am always curious about the latest tendencies concerning new technologies and gadgets, with an extra interest towards gaming gadgets